The 2026 NFL draft is in the books and
we have seven new Detroit Lions. Let's
have a look.
>> Welcome to the 2026 NFL draft.
>> Detroit Lions select Barry Sanders,
>> Kevin Johnson,
>> the Detroit Lions select Blake Miller.
Welcome to Detroit Lions Live presented
by Soaring Eagle Casino. I'm Cynthia
Freeland. Let's have a look at the new
draft class. The Lions started things
off by taking Blake Miller, the tackle,
out of Clemson at 6'7 and 315 pounds.
This guy had an athleticism score of
number four amongst tackles in this
class. He also had a NextGen stats total
score of 81, which ranked number two. in
college. He also was in the 95th
percentile in pass block win rate. I
think Jared Goff's going to like him.
Then there was Derek Moore in the second
round with 41 pressures last season,
including 11 sacks and 21 hurries along
with nine hits. Oh, and he had two force
fumbles for good measure. Then there was
Jimmy Roler, another Michigan man with
57 tackles and 13 pressures last season
along with two sacks when blitzing. And
then there's maybe my favorite steel of
the entire draft. its corner Keith Abney
II from Arizona State. This guy had two
interceptions and nine pass breakups
last season and he allowed a 46.1 passer
rating in coverage. Just so you know,
when a quarterback throws the ball into
the ground, it's just under 40. And then
we have Kendrick Law, the picture of
versatility. The wide receiver out of
Kentucky has a lot of special teams
upside including potentially being a
gunner. And then to finish off the
draft, two defensive tackles in round
six and seven in Skyler Gil Howard and
Tyrie West.
Our Tim 20man sat down with general
manager Brad Holmes after the draft.
They went through every single player
and Brad Holmes is very excited. He
said, "They are all us. The fit is
incredible." Let's have a look at the
conversation
here with Brad Holmes, general manager
of the Detroit Lions. just finished the
2026 NFL draft. Brad, you said you came
into this draft with a little bit of a a
fire having not made the playoffs last
year. How did that manifest itself in in
the preparation for this draft, how you
approached it, and the guys that you
ended up getting?
>> I would say from a preparation
standpoint in terms of I felt like we
always really did a lot from a
preparation standpoint. Um, worked
really, really hard, but just uh is
there another way to work even smarter
and not just, you know, harder? But we
still worked very very hard. Um I think
everybody can attest to to that that put
the work in. But um but just making some
tweaks and changes. I feel like the
results that came out of it from uh both
free agency and the draft um you know it
did a lot of it came from the bad taste
that was left, you know, uh from from
how the season ended.
>> You talked about uh guys that that fit
you right after the draft. Got football
players, you know. What was what was the
overall thought of ju of just the hall
that you got? What does that mean
getting getting a football player that
fits you?
>> Yeah, just a guy that plays the game the
right way. You know, there's players
that you have when you're football team
and there's football players and um
usually those guys when you say they're
football players, they play with a
certain type of urgency and toughness
and relentlessness. You know, you can
love football and have passion, but when
your passion for the game is showing in
your play, uh, then that's when you're
dealing with a football player.
>> Let's get into some of the picks. First
night, Blake Miller, uh, offensive
tackle for for at at Clemson. The thing
that jumps out is is obviously the 54
starts. I mean, guy came in,
>> was a left tackle in high school, saw a
spot open at right tackle, jumped in,
said, "Hey, this is my avenue to get on
the field." And and and never got off
it. Um, you know, just seems like like a
guy that that that fits what you guys
want along that offensive line with some
of the players you have in there.
Obviously with Hank Freley. Just talk
about why he's a great fit for you guys.
>> Yeah. Um, you know, everything that you
just said, you know, that's has kind of
been his story. He's he's all about the
work. He's all about earning it. Um, and
you know, again, all that experience
that he has, what was the cool thing
about through all that experience is
that he kept getting better. you know, I
looked at them. It was during the 24th
season, but we were uh looking at
offensive linemen and then I think they
played Georgia or something um in that
opener game, but was looking I started
off with this 23 tape. This kid, you
know, he's got some stuff, you know,
he's got to work on some things and then
you throw in that Georgia game in 24.
It's like, whoa, like that looked better
than the 23 stuff. And then you start
watching them all in 24 and then he goes
back to school. Then you watch the 20
the 25 that looks better than the 20.
And so I'm looking at the whole thing
like he has all this experience and you
know people say like you know well when
you have a high floor then that means
that the ceiling is low. No that's not
the case with him. Uh if he keeps
getting better then why is he not going
to keep getting better um here and you
know throughout the these next years.
>> How much advantage did you guys have
going into this draft when looking at
maybe adding an offensive tackle to have
a guy like Penny Su where obviously has
played some left tackle is an allp pro
at right tackle but we talked to you in
Arizona. We talked to Dan Campbell at
the in Arizona at the league meetings
and and he said, "Look, I think Penny
will need a day and then he'll be he'll
be good to figure it out at left tackle
again, but you could find the player
that fit you, right? You didn't have to
worry about finding a right tackle or
finding left tackle. What kind of
advantage was that?"
>> Yeah, it was it was it it was a huge
advantage. Um it's advantage that um not
many organizations have, but not many
organizations have a pineal. um haven't
seen a penal since pineal and so um just
to have a player that has that kind of
ability and yeah he has the the the
stuff in his body to go from left to
right and all that stuff but man it's
his it's his work ethic and how much he
loves the game and how how hard he
grinds like that when when you know that
he's got that plus the ability then
that's when it's like you don't you
don't even have to worry about you know
which side that he's playing. So, gave
us a lot of flexibility going into free
agency uh and and in the draft to just
get the best tackle that fits us.
>> Day two, you only had one pick. I loved
when you came up to the podium after the
Derek Moore pick. You had a smile on
your face because look, you've you've
gotten a little bit of grief for for for
not adding that guy, that bookend guy
right opposite Hutch. It it's been a
minute. So, I I loved that you came up
with a smile. had some fun with it, but
obviously you love the player and Derek
Moore. What does he bring to that
defense?
>> Yeah, you know, he's another one just
kind of like Blake Miller, just been
watching him for a while, just being
right right up the road there. And um
he's another one that just like Blake
Miller, as long as he's been playing, I
feel like he's at Michigan forever
playing on that. You've been seeing that
number eight on the edge of that
defense. And uh but he's another one
that kept getting better every single
year. as much as we've well I've filled
it all the when you going to get an edge
questions uh for I don't know how many
years now um you know look we're we're
we're not going to compromise what we're
about you know just as a as as from from
an identity standpoint from a football
player standpoint so we're we're we're
not going to get a player that just
plays a position just to say that we got
a player that plays a position we want
to get the right guy that plays you know
whichever position so Derek Moore fits
that you the the guy's long, he's
physical. I felt like he's always had
that. Um, you know, you always saw um
some some pass rush upside, but I just
felt like his pass rush arsenal really
came together this past year. And so,
um, watching, you know, again, you watch
him multiple times throughout the
process at different points of the year
and, um, it just it just kept growing
and growing and then the last time you
see him actually playing football is at
the Senior Bowl. And so already kind of
convinced or you know know that like man
this guy's really gotten better at the
pass rushing and you go down to mobile
and you see him live and he's just he's
getting after it rushing the passer
verse legit competition. So um it was it
was it was really cool to see. So really
excited.
>> 10 sacks but also 10 and a half tackles
for loss for him too. Having that guy
that can vision that guy that fits you
on the edge. Is that a guy that can also
set an edge and be good against the run
too? Is that is that kind of what what
you have to have in that position to fit
you?
>> Yeah. Look, you you you have to earn the
right to rush the passer. And so he's
got both. And and that's when that's
kind of what his floor has been. You
know, his floor has always been like,
yeah, he can set the edge, he can play
the run, but you know, you can't just be
a hammerhead on the edge and just not,
you know, like you got to you got to get
to the quarterback as well. You know,
that's why those guys are hard to find,
man. Like sometimes you're getting
either or, you know, it's like, well,
yeah, good rundown player, but he can't
get a quarterback or this guy's a good
designated pass rusher, but he can't
play the run. So, when you're looking
for the guys that we look for that can
offer you a little bit of both, um, you
know, you got to be patient, but, you
know, um, but I don't think you should
compromise what the identity is and he
can bring that.
>> You open up day three, fourth round, you
go with, you go backto back Wolverines.
What What did you like about him? How
does he fit? Look, you're you're you're
looking to fill that will spot. Is he a
guy that you look that can maybe fill
that will spot?
>> I just like the football player, man. He
just fits what what what we're about,
man. Um he's tough. He's instinctive.
He's physical. Um his his intangibles
and his work ethic. Uh like what we call
football character, pass for the game,
like that's all high. I really didn't
even expect when we were just waiting
and waiting and waiting during the third
round. I just knew I was going to see
his name flash across there and so when
it wasn't then I was like wow he's still
there you know got up this morning and
that was cool to see but didn't know if
he was going to last to our pick and so
just really really thrilled to get him
he's another guy that's a four core
special teams player so um you know we
like those kind of
>> those highlights on special teams with
him running through some guys bringing
some defenders right into the ball here
that had to make you pretty excited
>> that's another thing Tim like when you
start talking about football players,
man. Like some guys, they don't want to
play special teams, you know, and and
those guys that just just want to play
offense or just play defense and don't
want to play special teams, that says
something about you as a football
player. And so the guys that are just
relentless on special teams, too, that's
what special teams is, man. Like, yeah,
you got to have a certain body type on
certain positions on special teams. Um,
but so there's some traits that you like
to have, but at the end of the day, it's
your attitude. And um and Jimmy Roller
has that.
>> Keith Abby the the second. Another guy I
don't think you expected him to be there
when when you selected. How excited were
you for that? And is is he a guy he
played the most of the time on the
outside? Is he a guy that you project
maybe can play inside?
>> I think he can do both. I'm not pigeon
holeing him or putting him in a boxing
and he's just a nickel only. Um he's got
enough good tape out there um versus for
some really good wide receivers of him
playing on the outside. But but I do
think that uh from a projection
standpoint, I do think he can play
inside as well. But um but I just think
that's just a bonus. Speaking of wide
receivers, then you picked one up and
and Kendrick Log, a guy that was kind of
a gimmicky guy at Alabama, went to
Kentucky and, you know, they use him on
a lot of screens and jet sweeps and some
of that stuff, but do you see a vertical
element to his game at all or or or do
you and obviously special teams we
talked about earlier, a guy that has
some return ability to just how do you
see him fitting in? I hate to sound like
a broken record, but I'm gonna say it
again, a football player. So, rather you
got to have him um taken off the line of
scrimmage and trying to get get
vertical, which I think he can. Um at
least he can open some some things up.
He's going to be a really cool kind of
chess piece to have offensively, but you
said it Tim, love his special teams as
well. Again, he's got the attitude. He
will go and play Gunner and run down
there. And again, it just it fits the
theme of, you know, when we when we pick
Jameson Williams, you know, uh like like
J Mo, everybody talks about how fast he
is as a wide receiver. Yes, he is that
he is electric. He's dynamic as a wide
receiver, but you watch turn on that
Alabama tape, he's at gunner running
down like he has the attitude. So, um so
so Law just kind of fits that football
play.
>> Be a differencemaker as a Gunner League.
I mean, it just takes one special teams
play to change the course of a game. And
it sounds like you added some guys that
you think maybe can do that. All right,
take me through the last two guys here,
Skyler Gil Howard and and Tyrie West,
two defensive linemen that you kind of
finished uh Saturday with. What do you
what do you like about those two guys?
>> Yeah. Um kind of unique with uh with Gil
Howard in terms I think he's got a
unique journey. um you know was was was
at a um smaller program, but even at
smaller program was when he had to play
top competition, he showed up there and
then you know he gets to Texas Tech and
um and had a lot of good players around
him as well, but he fit right in. But
the tape he had out there, I mean, you
just saw a relentless football player
that, you know, can win inside, win
quick. He will grind it in there and and
do the dirty stuff at the point of
attack, too, because he has leverage,
natural leverage the way he's built. So
really excited to get him. And then Tyer
West is another guy that again um you
know Tennessee had all those defensive
linemen rotating. So you're looking at a
lot of them and then it's like every
time this 42 comes in the game he's kind
of winning winning a rush and getting
back to the quarterback. So um you know
so really really really excited. Uh
we'll just kind of see how far it goes
but they they they have the right stuff
um to get themselves a chance.
>> Two more quick ones here to finish up.
You always talk about best player
available and and you're hard-nosed
about that. We're going to take the
player that we feel convicted about, but
you came into this draft with with some
obvious needs. Was this one of those
drafts where just best player available,
maybe tailored up to some need and and
how advantageous is that when when it
does fall that way, Brad?
>> It just lined up, man. Um, look, there
was there there may have been some some
even ties at other position, but so if
there's even ties where there's other
players that play other positions, but
it's like, look, I could I could pick
one of them out of a hat and be thrilled
with it, but then when it kind of hits
some some some positions that might be a
little bit more critical than others or
like, you know, with the buzzes more
more premium than than others, then it
it makes it it makes it pretty easy. So,
um, what we did not do is we did not get
lesser players that we liked lesser
because they played those positions and,
uh, compromise getting better football
players cuz they played other positions.
That's when you can get yourself in
trouble.
>> Looking at this class as a whole, let's
finish with this and and the big
picture, you look at all seven guys, I
think it was, what's the one word you
you'd use to describe this class?
>> Football player.
>> And that's what you want to build this
roster. every single one of these guys
football player. It sounds like a very
simplistic,
you know, word, you know, two words,
football player. Well, yeah, you're on a
football. It's a football organization.
You need players to play on the
football. No, there's something
different when you say this guy's a
football player. And that's that's the
best way I can say about about all these
guys, man. These guys are football
players, man. These guys are gritty and
they fit exactly what we're about.
Blake Miller made his way to Allen Park
on Friday to meet his new staff and see
his new home. And we got a chance to get
to know him. And he brought along a
special guest.
>> Before we get started here, I'm actually
going to bring in somebody that knows
you a little bit better than I do to to
help us out. Mom.
>> So, they have some questions I'm going
to ask you. Has it set in that you're a
Detroit lion yet? Yeah, it's definitely
began to set in a little bit. Um, it's a
it's a surreal moment really, but you
know, being here, being able to see
everything, you know, tour the facility,
meet everyone, it's it's been
incredible. It's it's really starting to
set in.
>> What are your impressions being in the
building as a Lion for the first time?
>> Obviously, you know, the facility is
incredible, very impressive. You know,
all the the weight room, the training
room, the indoor, the meeting rooms,
like everything is is beautiful,
top-notch. you know, just meeting
everyone here, you can you can see the
the fire everyone has in their eyes and,
you know, the determination that
everyone has. It's truly throughout the
whole staff and it's it's awesome.
>> What does a successful first season look
like to you?
>> I'd say for me, a successful first
season is earning the trust and respect
of my teammates and coaches. whatever
role I'm called to be in. If I'm a guy
that my teammates trust when I run out
there and you know they're not looking
to me come critical situations, they
know I'm going to get my job done. I
feel like I'll have been successful in
my first year.
>> When you look back later in your NFL
career, what do you never want to forget
about last night in being drafted?
>> Say the looks on everyone's faces around
me, you know, just just seeing the
happiness and the surprise and the
excitement in everyone else's eyes like
that. I don't know that that really it
brings a smile to my face to to think
back to that moment. So, I'll cherish
that memory.
>> What final message would you like to
send to Lions fans about who you are and
your excitement to play in Detroit?
>> Over the moon to to play in Detroit. You
know, Coach Campbell here has built an
amazing culture and I just, you know,
really want to uphold his his standards
and his, you know, tenants that he's set
for this team and be a a finisher, be be
a guy who has grit, be a guy who's
physical. I want a team after they get
done playing us to walk off the field
and know that they just played the
Detroit Lions.
>> Very good. And I just wanted to say how
incredibly proud I am of you and uh you
have come so far
for I remember dropping you off at
Clemson and to see what you are today.
It's just been amazing. So
congratulations.
>> Thanks, Mom.
>> You guys want a holiday?
I need a baby. I love you, too.
Congratulations.
>> Thank you.
>> Mom's hired.
>> There are few things better than
football and family. It's impossible not
to like Blake Miller. But it's also
impossible not to like Timman and
watching film with him. What a great day
for me. What's going on, Tim? Let's
break down this class.
>> Let's break it down. We'll start with
Blake Miller. And you know, I love that
you are here because people might not
know this, but Cynthia studied offensive
lineman in college. So, us breaking this
down together, this is this is perfect.
I'm going to love this.
>> This is great.
>> This is great. Well, you know, I think
the one advantage the Lions had when you
talk about Blake Miller and the
offensive tackles going into this draft
is they had Penny Su, you know, and
here's a guy who was an allp pro at
right tackle, right? But you can flip
him to left tackle. That's where he
played uh the first half of his rookie
season. I talked to Dan Campbell at the
league meetings. He said, "Yeah, he'll
maybe need a day to figure that out and
get back to being left tackle." And I
think we all can assume he's going to be
probably an allp pro left tackle, too.
So, going into this draft, you could
find the right player for you. You
didn't have to find a right tackle or a
left tackle. And when you look at Blake
Miller, I think it just fit what Detroit
Lions want in their offensive line. A
guy who started 54 straight games. You
talked about it earlier, missed what,
two practices, an entire career. It's
like there's some there's something
about like one or two practice. Doesn't
matter. It's two practices max.
>> Yeah. And what you love with him is the
size, the ability to anchor right at 67
almost 320 pounds. But the athleticism,
Cynthia, is something that I think
really fits this team as well. Look at
his ability to get out on the edge, turn
his hips, lock in, let that running back
get inside of him, and look at push that
defensive end right behind the
quarterback. He's just completely out of
the play. allow that quarterback to step
up if he wanted to. Instead there, he
just completed a pass in the flat and it
was a big play. I think what he just
gives you is is versatility and this is
one of the plays I love the most. You
saw Pen Sul do this so many times to the
Detroit Lions office. Get out in space,
get to that second and third level. Guys
like Jir Gibbs and Isaiah Pacheco are
going to love the fact that they can do
this on the left side and they can do
this now on the right side. I think it
just opens up Detroit's offense so much
more. You got a guy with size. You got a
guy who's durable. You got a guy who has
who's athletic. He just fits the profile
of what the Detroit Lions are looking
for as a right tackle.
>> One of the cool things that I saw when
watching the film is the fact that the
transfer portal has now made it crazy
with resumes. But because he played at
the same school year over year, you got
a chance to see him evolve into a guy
who could create space and go into that
second level, which isn't something you
necessarily see with all offensive
linemen. I mean, even all first
rounders, right? because they transfer
schools or their quarterback changes,
the playbook has become slimmer and
slimmer. So now you're seeing
versatility. You're seeing a lot of
different use cases which are way easier
for Drew Pig to be like, I can work with
that 67 350. Yeah, I can work with that,
too. So, I'm looking at it from that
standpoint and saying, not only do you
have the durability, which we always
know that ability is, you know, the the
most important ability is that you're on
the field and that you're right there
all the time, but ultimately you're now
able to do a lot of different things and
keep the offense fresh and defense is
guessing.
>> Yeah, 100%. I just He just fits
everything that that Detroit wants to do
offensively, what Drew Pessing wants to
do. It's a versatile offense. he you
know they're going to run some 12
personnel they might run 13 personnel
they're going to do 11 you're going to
do a lot of different variations in
Ping's offense and I think just with his
size his athleticism his anchor his bend
his ability kind of to do everything
just fits whatever you want to do
>> sounds a little crazy but he has great
ankle bends one of the things
>> this is from your studies right
>> this is so nerdy I'm all in on being a
nerd here but if you measure the angle
the angles of your joints in your knees
your ankles and your lower back it often
is an indicator ator for if you're going
to be a waistband or not. And he has all
of the indicators that he doesn't become
a waistband, meaning getting unfavorable
leverage and allowing your quarterback
to be sacked. Right. So, he has all of
the good metrics. What
>> I'm loving this.
>> It's nerdy for sure, but he has all of
those right metrics with all of the long
levers, especially considering how tall
he is. Sometimes ankles can be bad and
and different, but he has he has no
problems there. But Tim, who are we to
talk about tackles when we have one of
the best Lions tackles of all time, Lis
Brown, the pride of the Lions, Ring of
Honor member. Let's hear what he has to
say.
>> First of all, congratulations, Blake.
Welcome to Detroit. Um, and I I just
think the thing that I love about him is
his durability. Uh, I played 18 years in
the league. This man had 54 starts in
college and that's unheard of. So to me,
the durability is there, the will, the
want um is there for him to show up
every day. Heard he only missed one
practice out of his career. That's
that's just awesome. So he's definitely
has the mentality of a allpro uh Pro
Bowl type of offensive lineman. So, just
looking forward to meeting him. And like
I say, welcome to Detroit.
>> Moving on to day two. I mean, the the
Lions just had to go up the road to Ann
Arbor.
>> Hop, skip, and a jump.
>> Hop, skip, and a jump away. Let's have a
look at Derek Moore.
>> Yeah, with Derek Moore. And look,
Cynthia, Lions fans are are loving this
one because not since 2022 have the
Lions taken an edge rusher in the first
two days of the draft. Aiden Hutchinson,
me might know him. Allp pro kind of guy
here. But people have been clamoring for
kind of that bookend guy, that guy
opposite Hutch, right? They signed DJ
Wum in free agency. They expect him to
be a contributor, veteran guy who's had
some success in this league. But who's
that young guy? Who's that next guy
opposite Hutch? And um you know, when
you look at Derek Moore, I I some of the
things that jump out with him, at least
initially, is Cynthia, look at this
first step. Boom. And all of a sudden,
you have that offensive lineman on his
heels back. And that's what every edge
rusher, defensive lineman wants. He's
got that great quick step. I think he
transitions power and speed perfectly. I
think this is a great example here. You
know, you can rush him inside, outside.
I think he's great on stunts and some of
the games that you're going to play. I
just think he sits from fits from a
size, speed, athletic profile. And one
of the things that I love too is he got
better every year. And Brad Holmes
talked about that too, that he's one of
those guys along with Blake Miller that
they had their eye on for the last three
years and and when you're studying guys,
you want to see that improvement, that
technique work. You talked about it
earlier, a guy being in in a system for
a while and and just being able to grow
within it. Coaches have a better
understanding of what you can do. And,
you know, they moved him around a lot
more this season because they understood
what he can do. He he had grown every
year. And um I just think he's a great
fit. I think he can play um opposite
Hutch. I think in some of the sub
packages he can fit in. Give Hutch a
little bit of break. Hutch plays 90
plus% of the snaps. I mean, he he's
ridiculous. And and so now you get a guy
with a similar type skill set. Look,
he's not Hutchinson. I don't want to put
that on the kid, but there's a similar
skill set there in terms of, you know,
you can play him on different sides. He
can stand up. He can play the
three-point stance. I think he can do a
lot of different things with him. And
and Brad Holmes and Lions are certainly
excited with with this young guy. Well,
who plays base defense anymore, right?
Almost no one. So, even if he's
contributing on certain specific
packages to begin with, and then he
rolls in more and more and you keep that
evolution of versatility going, you're
going to leverage the explosiveness that
you see. The other thing that really
flagged for him as being an upside in
terms of metrics is his reaction time.
So both in getting his hands to push
against an an offensive player or also
when he gets a little bit knocked or
pushed by one of the offensive linemen,
his second effort in order to win the
rep. So he has great reaction times
including with the explosive first step.
So that's what you're talking about with
the transition from power to production.
>> Yeah. One of the non-negotiables for,
you know, Calvin Shepard in this Lion's
defense is you've got to be able to set
an edge too and you've got to be able to
play the run. So you look at him,
>> you want an edge rusher to set the edge.
Who would have thought?
>> So you look at him and you love the 10
sacks, right? And and the pass rush
production that you saw increase every
year at Michigan, but 10 and a half
tackles for loss, too. This kid can set
an edge. And I think just look at the
last two Super Bowl winners, right? You
look at Philadelphia and Seattle, what
was their strength? What were they be
able to do? They were able to throw
different waves of pass rushers with
different kinds of skill sets
through. So, you know, this is a guy
with DJ Warhammer, who we talked about,
some other guys, what they added in the
interior. Now, you're building some
depth that you could just throw some
different skill sets and and guys with
different rush abilities at an offense.
And I think that's where this kid is
going to really fit into this defense
and make an impact.
>> I love that. Well, Lis Brown probably
knows a thing or two about Derek Moore,
too, because he had to block these guys
when he was in the league. I mean, from
everything I'm hearing, especially that
first step, heard that he he has a great
first step. Um, he's a guy that we
definitely uh needed somebody opposite
of Aiden to kind of take some of that
pressure off of him. Of course, a
University of Michigan guy, so those
guys have that bond going for
themselves. But, uh, the great thing is
he knows from being here in Michigan and
watching the Lions, I'm quite sure from
afar, what's been one of our glaring
needs and it's been a guy opposite of
Aiden Hutcherson. So, you know, he seems
to be a guy that can use his hands good.
He has the pedigree seems like because
again, a University of Michigan guy. So,
just looking forward to what he'll be
able to bring to that defensive line,
especially the defensive pass rush. Uh
because that's what we're going to have
to do this year. I think for 2026, we're
going to have to affect the opposing
quarterbacks. Uh get them off their
spots, sacks, hits, pressures, all
that's going to have to happen for us to
have success. Um I think in 2026,
>> we made it, Tim. We made it to the one
that makes you a real one, which is day
three. If you are a draft nick and you
know everything about the draft, none of
these names are going to even surprise
you at all, but we should probably get
to know them a little bit better.
>> And Brad loved day three. There were
guys, he talked after day three, he said
there were guys we did not expect would
be there. I love what we got in day
three. So, let's look at some of these
guys.
>> Absolutely. Obviously, starting in the
fourth round again, another Michigan
man. It's just like they love Michigan
or something like that. Jimmy Ralder
here. interesting take on him. What did
you see from it?
>> Well, two things. I think his coverage
ability stands out to me. The way he can
drop and play the second level. We're
going to see it here. Just the the
ability to keep the eyes on the
quarterback, read his keys, see it right
away, and boom, and finish. I love that.
That's a Detroit Lion right there. When
you finish your tackle, and finish the
play, and then some of the tape that I
watch with special teams, I mean, that
jumps out when you're talking day three
guys. Right now, Detroit's got an open
spot at the will. he'll jump in and
compete with Malcolm Rodriguez and some
other guys for that. But when you're
talking about day three guys, the
immediate impact sometimes and the way
they're going to get on the field is
special teams and some of the things
that we're seeing in these highlights
certainly transition over to special
teams as well. The physicality, the
speed, open field tackling. I think he's
really good at all those kind of things
and I think he's a perfect fit here in
that linebacking room. I like his
blitzing ability, too, because sometimes
you don't get that at his position, the
ability to just have that explosiveness
and be able to see to that second level
because you're standing in the second
level, so you got to get back there to
see the quarterback. So, I really
appreciated that from his film. I also
thought he had good change of direction
speed. Sometimes people slow down
considerably when they move laterally or
backwards, and he doesn't have as many
of the indicators for slowing down in
those situations as some of the other
guys that would have gone in a similar
round as him. Yeah, I love that you
mentioned the blitzing and the sack part
of it, too. You look at Detroit's
linebackers last year. Jack Campbell won
five sacks. Calvin Shepard likes to
bring those guys and likes to bring them
from a lot of different areas and so
having multiple guys that can do that is
huge for this defense.
>> I also feel like if coach Shepard likes
it, we have to like it too because he's
forgotten more about linebackers than we
will ever know. So, let's move on to our
next one here. When you're looking at my
favorite pick, my favorite value maybe
of this entire draft.
>> Me, too. Look at us. Are we twins?
>> I like this guy.
>> This is good for me cuz you're a legend.
But ultimately, this could be my
favorite pick of like the entire draft
from a value standpoint. The opportunity
for Heath Abney the second to be
incredible is certainly there. The
upside is absolutely there. There's some
risk there, but what did you see in the
film from him?
>> Physical.
>> Yeah. I mean, this is an aggressive guy
and it starts right there. That's
probably the one clip Dan loved, Brad
loved, is is him putting the thunder on
a guy after a catch. But look, he's very
physical. It led to some penalties in
college. And look, all these guys coming
in, the college game at this position is
much different than the program. You got
five yards here and that's it. The
college lets these guys be a little bit
more physical. And I think they they
almost teach it at the college level a
little bit more because of the rules.
But I think that's going to be an
adjustment for him, but he's got size.
He's physical. And this I think that
Cynthia is going to allow him to move
inside and play the nickel. And I
wouldn't be surprised if from day one we
see this kid playing more in the nickel
and he's competing with McCreary and
Izzy and some of those guys for that
starting nickel spot because I just
think the physicality, the speed, the
size, everything just kind of fits him
being able to uh uh you know step inside
and play the run. He's very physical on
the edge in in run defense as well.
Another prerequisite in Kelvin Shepard's
defense. So, I just think his skill set,
his toolbox, all kind of fits to to
being that nickel guy at the NFL level.
>> And remember, the wide receiver coach
for Arizona State was Hines Ward. So, if
you're looking at what kind of things
happen, like you saw Jordan Tyson, the
wide receiver, take a big step forward
with Hines Ward there. You know who he
faced in practice every day? This guy.
So, in practice, he's seen more of that
pro style, too. So, perhaps we don't
even know from the resume film what they
did in practice. So, there's even more
upside there in my opinion, having that
pedigree there. I think when we get to
training camp, some of those battles
between him and Aman Ross St. Brown,
right? Two physical guys right in the
middle of that field. I think that's
going to be fun to watch. That's going
to be must see TV come training camp.
>> And then now we're getting a little
deeper into it. The sixth round. I love
watching the sixth and seventh round
because I was at the draft and you get
to meet astronauts, but all these
players are being selected. Great job,
by the way.
>> Thank you. That was it was very fun. Not
as good as Detroit, don't worry. But
Pittsburgh did put on a good show. It
was a ton of fun. But we have uh you
talk about special teams, special teams
versatility, wide receiver here,
Kendrick Law out of Kentucky. What did
you see from him?
>> You know, he started his career at
Alabama and then, you know, transferred
to Kentucky. It was really a gimmicky
kind of player at Alabama, a guy who
would do the jet sweeps and the screens
and there wasn't a lot of downfield, you
know, you know, throwing the ball to
him. I think there's a little bit more
to to that that that Detroit's going to
maybe try to unlock just because of his
speed element. But talk about a guy with
just quickness. A a guy that can
separate at the top of a route, that can
create some space. And then it's the run
after the catch. I mean, you see it, you
see the control there, but look at that.
The ability to jump over guys, just
ability to get in space. Here it is. See
it be able to cut outside, find his
blocks, and then turn it on in the
speed. You know, I I think there's a
little bit more element to his game than
we saw in in in college. And certainly
Detroit and Drew Petting are going to
try to unlock that. I think he's coming
into a great situation here where he can
maybe kind of fill that Khalif Raymond
role, you know, be an inside guy to to
supplement um Aman Ross St. Brown and
then the special teams element. Um being
a kick returner. Look, the kickoff is
back in the NFL. It's a huge
>> the rule change is here to stay
>> and it's a difference maker. I mean, you
get a huge play on special teams that
can be the difference in a game and I
think this kid, not only as a returner,
Cynthia, but also a gunner. I think he's
got that potential as well. And so I
just see a kind of a dual role. Probably
more special teams initially. That's how
this kid's going to make the roster and
get on. But I think some of the elements
that you see with him in space and just
get the ball in his hands. Drew Petting
is great at those matchups and getting
guys in space. I think he fits that
element.
>> I think it's very fun to watch a guy
with all the speed and the different
ways you can you can deploy him and then
now put him in a system where he stays
in the same system for longer. Clearly
uh my thoughts on the transfer reporter
are very transparent here. I don't love
it. But ultimately, you'll be able to
see more of his game unfold as he stays
in one system longer. Okay. So, in the
sixth and seventh round, they shifted
back to the defensive side of the ball.
Starting with Skyler Gil Howard, Texas
Tech defensive tackle. What do you like
about him?
>> I love the story about him. Right. I
mean, here you go. you got a division
two linebacker that decides there's no
avenue for him in the transfer portal um
for the first round for the second round
and then you get uh Northern Illinois
says you know we like your tape but we'd
like you to play defensive tackle can
you just gain 50 pounds and play
defensive tackle for us and the kid's
like yeah no problem so he does and you
know he works his way in this is a kid
who's only played defensive tackle for
three seasons and so I think with him.
You see a ton of upside. You love the
first step and the swim move there. I
think he comes with a pretty good
toolbox of pass rush moves for a kid
who's only played the position for three
years. And then the linebacker, the
former running back there. You, me and
you, I think we could agree. We love big
guys with the football in their hands.
That's a that's a defensive lineman's
dream. That ball just comes there. But
he showed off. He was a running back in
high school. He was a linebacker to
start his career. I think there's some
athleticism. There's some quick twitch,
a good first step. But like you
mentioned too, special teams, that's
where, you know, these guys in the
sixth, seventh round. I think because of
the rules, special teams has become more
of a, you know, a space, you're seeing
tight ends, you're seeing, you know, a
little bit more athletic, big guys make
special teams. I think he fits that
mold. I think he's a guy, even as a
bigger guy at 280 pounds, I think he's a
guy that could play some special teams
with this athleticism. So, I think
there's, you know, some some dual
elements to his role. He's going to get
in here. He's going to get into a good
defensive line room, a good system, and
learn from those guys. But I think
there's some upside with his game.
Certainly,
>> one of my favorite strategies is to
double down on positions of need,
especially in these later rounds,
because you're just increasing your odds
of getting it right. And defensive
tackle is something to absolutely get
right. So, that is exactly what the
Lions did in the seventh round, taking
another defensive tackle, Tyrie West.
Tell me what you like about this
volunteer game. position versatility.
You know, I think that with him in
particular, I think you can see him, you
know, inside and they had a deep
defensive line rotation at Tennessee.
And so, you know, Brad talked about that
too that you didn't see him a ton. I
think he averaged less than 25 snaps a
game, but when 42 was on the field, he
was a differencemaker. And look, you see
him out on the edge here. And I think
that's what he brings is a little bit of
position versatility. The Lions love
that in really all three levels of their
defense. the more you can do, right,
Cynthia? And I think that's the story
with this. Get he's got it for good
first step. You see it there getting
past the guard. You love the Sally
there, too. But you'd be able to throw
him at the big end, be able to put him
on the edge in sub packages, and then
you move him inside. Now, you can play
some games with some different things. I
think he's got that skill set to be able
to do a bunch of different things.
They'll figure it out in training camp,
but I expect to see him kind of all
along that defensive line initially.
>> I love versatility. I also love the fact
that I get to do this with you because
it's so fun to hear national narratives
versus local narratives for my favorite
team here, the Lions, of course. But I
rarely get to see Brad Holmes be
excited. And dare I say, he was excited
when talking about these prospects,
especially day three. You should check
it out.
>> When you get to day three, I just, you
know, you can throw a lot of the stuff
out the window. you know, well, what
round did you have them in or what grade
did you have? Look, man, just pick the
player that you want, you know, and so
that's kind of our our mindset. So, I
just thought it was going to be a fun
time just to I don't know if they're
going to be seventh round guys, sixth
round guys, whatever, but we were able
to get some guys that we had ranked a
way higher um that fell for whatever
reason. Um I'm not really worried about
that. We're not worried about that.
We're just thrilled that we have them.
So, that's kind of how it exceeded my
expectations. But all of them, every
single last one of them, they are
complete true fits. Like the these these
guys are lions. Like I know technically
they are, yes, but they they they fit
everything that we're about. So, um, we
got some good football players.
>> Thank you so much for joining us and
getting to know your newest Detroit
Lions, the football players that fit
this team so well. Thank you so much for
allowing me to host this show. I love
representing the Lions as a girl from
Okamus should. Thank you so much. And I
can't wait for our football season to
start.
>> With the 17th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Detroit Lions select Blake
Mele.
>> All right, man. Are you ready to line?
Oh, hell yeah, I am.
>> Detroit Lions select Derek Moore.
>> The Detroit Lions select Jimmy Roller.
>> This awesome opportunity. Can't tell you
how excited I am. Detroit Lions select
Keith Abney II.
>> Feeling all the emotions, man. It's a
dream come true.
>> Detroit Lions select Kendrick Law. The
>> Detroit Lions select Skyler G. Howard.
>> The Detroit Lions select Tyrie West.
>> This right here is really just dream
coming true. Still don't even feel real.
>> Let's do this one right away, baby.